<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Get started on Tommas's Blog</title><link>https://t.is-local.org/en/docs/get-started/</link><description>Recent content in Get started on Tommas's Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 10:20:15 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://t.is-local.org/en/docs/get-started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Other setup options</title><link>https://t.is-local.org/en/docs/get-started/other-options/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 09:22:27 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://t.is-local.org/en/docs/get-started/other-options/</guid><description>If you don&amp;rsquo;t want to use Docsy as a Hugo Module (for example if you do not want to install Go) but still don&amp;rsquo;t want to copy the theme files into your own repo, you can use Docsy as a Git submodule. Using submodules also lets Hugo use the theme files from Docsy repo, though is more complicated to maintain than the Hugo Modules approach. This is the approach used in older versions of the Docsy example site, and is still supported.</description></item><item><title>Deploy Docsy inside a Docker container</title><link>https://t.is-local.org/en/docs/get-started/quickstart-docker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://t.is-local.org/en/docs/get-started/quickstart-docker/</guid><description>We provide a Docker image that you can use to run and test your Docsy site locally, without having to install all Docsy&amp;rsquo;s dependencies.
Install the prerequisites On Mac and Windows, download and install Docker Desktop. On Linux, install Docker engine and Docker compose.
The installation may require you to reboot your computer for the changes to take effect.
Install git.
Create your repository from the docsy-example template The docsy-example repository provides a basic site structure that you can use as starting point to create your own documentation.</description></item><item><title>Basic site configuration</title><link>https://t.is-local.org/en/docs/get-started/basic-configuration/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 09:22:27 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://t.is-local.org/en/docs/get-started/basic-configuration/</guid><description>Site-wide configuration details and parameters are defined in your project&amp;rsquo;s configuration file (hugo.toml or config.toml). These include your chosen Hugo theme (Docsy, of course!), project name, community links, Google Analytics configuration, and Markdown parser parameters. See the examples with comments in hugo.toml in the example project for how to add this information. We recommend copying this hugo.toml and editing it even if you’re just using the theme and not copying the entire Docsy example site, as it includes default values for many parameters that you need to set for your site to build correctly.</description></item><item><title>Known issues</title><link>https://t.is-local.org/en/docs/get-started/known_issues/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 09:22:27 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://t.is-local.org/en/docs/get-started/known_issues/</guid><description>The following issues are know on MacOS and on Windows Subsystem for Linux:
MacOS Errors: too many open files or fatal error: pipe failed By default, MacOS permits a small number of open File Descriptors. For larger sites, or when you&amp;rsquo;re simultaneously running multiple applications, you might receive one of the following errors when you run hugo server to preview your site locally:
POSTCSS v7 and earlier:
ERROR 2020/04/14 12:37:16 Error: listen tcp 127.</description></item></channel></rss>