<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Content and Customization on Tommas's Blog</title><link>https://t.is-local.org/en/docs/adding-content/</link><description>Recent content in Content and Customization on Tommas's Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://t.is-local.org/en/docs/adding-content/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Adding Content</title><link>https://t.is-local.org/en/docs/adding-content/content/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://t.is-local.org/en/docs/adding-content/content/</guid><description>So you&amp;rsquo;ve got a new Hugo website with Docsy, now it&amp;rsquo;s time to add some content! This page tells you how to use the theme to add and structure your site content.
Content root directory You add content for your site under the content root directory of your Hugo site project - either content/ or a language-specific root like content/en/. The main exception here is static files that you don&amp;rsquo;t want built into your site: you can find out more about where you add these below in Adding static content.</description></item><item><title>Look and Feel</title><link>https://t.is-local.org/en/docs/adding-content/lookandfeel/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://t.is-local.org/en/docs/adding-content/lookandfeel/</guid><description>By default, a site using Docsy has the theme&amp;rsquo;s default fonts, colors, and general look and feel. However, if you want your own color scheme (and you probably will!) you can very easily override the theme defaults with your own project-specific values - Hugo will look in your project files first when looking for information to build your site. And because Docsy uses Bootstrap 5 and SCSS for styling, you can override just single values (such as project colors and fonts) in its special SCSS project variables file, or do more serious customization by creating your own styles.</description></item><item><title>Navigation and Menus</title><link>https://t.is-local.org/en/docs/adding-content/navigation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://t.is-local.org/en/docs/adding-content/navigation/</guid><description>Docsy provides multiple built-in navigation features for your sites, including site menus, section menus, and page menus. This page shows you how they work and how to configure and customize them to meet your needs.
Top-level menu The top level menu (the one that appears in the top navigation bar for the entire site) uses your site&amp;rsquo;s main menu. All Hugo sites have a main menu array of menu entries, accessible via the .</description></item><item><title>Search</title><link>https://t.is-local.org/en/docs/adding-content/search/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://t.is-local.org/en/docs/adding-content/search/</guid><description>Docsy offers multiple options that let your readers search your site content, so you can pick one that suits your needs. You can choose from:
Google Custom Search Engine (GCSE), the default option, which uses Google&amp;rsquo;s index of your public site to generate a search results page. Algolia DocSearch, which uses Algolia&amp;rsquo;s indexing and search mechanism. Search results are displayed as a pop-up. Algolia DocSearch is free for public documentation sites.</description></item><item><title>Doc Versioning</title><link>https://t.is-local.org/en/docs/adding-content/versioning/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://t.is-local.org/en/docs/adding-content/versioning/</guid><description>Depending on your project&amp;rsquo;s releases and versioning, you may want to let your users access previous versions of your documentation. How you deploy the previous versions is up to you. This page describes the Docsy features that you can use to provide navigation between the various versions of your docs and to display an information banner on the archived sites.
Adding a version drop-down menu If you add some [params.versions] in hugo.</description></item><item><title>Docsy Shortcodes</title><link>https://t.is-local.org/en/docs/adding-content/shortcodes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://t.is-local.org/en/docs/adding-content/shortcodes/</guid><description>Rather than writing all your site pages from scratch, Hugo lets you define and use shortcodes. These are reusable snippets of content that you can include in your pages, often using HTML to create effects that are difficult or impossible to do in simple Markdown. Shortcodes can also have parameters that let you, for example, add your own text to a fancy shortcode text box. As well as Hugo&amp;rsquo;s built-in shortcodes, Docsy provides some shortcodes of its own to help you build your pages.</description></item><item><title>Logos and Images</title><link>https://t.is-local.org/en/docs/adding-content/iconsimages/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://t.is-local.org/en/docs/adding-content/iconsimages/</guid><description>Add your logo By default, Docsy shows a site logo at the start of the navbar, that is, at the extreme left. Place your project&amp;rsquo;s SVG logo in assets/icons/logo.svg. This overrides the default Docsy logo in the theme.
If you don&amp;rsquo;t want a logo to appear in the navbar, then set site parameter navbar_logo to false in your project&amp;rsquo;s config:
Configuration file: hugo.toml hugo.yaml hugo.json [params.ui] navbar_logo = false params: ui: navbar_logo: false { &amp;#34;params&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;ui&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;navbar_logo&amp;#34;: false } } } For information about styling your logo, see Styling your project logo and name.</description></item><item><title>Print Support</title><link>https://t.is-local.org/en/docs/adding-content/print/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://t.is-local.org/en/docs/adding-content/print/</guid><description>Individual documentation pages print well from most browsers as the layouts have been styled to omit navigational chrome from the printed output.
On some sites, it can be useful to enable a &amp;ldquo;print entire section&amp;rdquo; feature (as seen in this user guide). Selecting this option renders the entire current top-level section (such as Content and Customization for this page) with all of its child pages and sections in a format suited to printing, complete with a table of contents for the section.</description></item><item><title>Analytics, User Feedback, and SEO</title><link>https://t.is-local.org/en/docs/adding-content/feedback/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://t.is-local.org/en/docs/adding-content/feedback/</guid><description>Adding Analytics The Docsy theme builds upon Hugo&amp;rsquo;s support for Google Analytics, which Hugo provides through internal templates. Once you set up analytics as described below, usage information for your site (such as page views) is sent to your Google Analytics account.
Prerequisites You will need an analytics ID for your website before proceeding (technically it&amp;rsquo;s called a measurement ID or property ID but we&amp;rsquo;ll use the term &amp;ldquo;analytics ID&amp;rdquo; in this guide).</description></item><item><title>Repository Links and other page information</title><link>https://t.is-local.org/en/docs/adding-content/repository-links/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://t.is-local.org/en/docs/adding-content/repository-links/</guid><description>The Docsy docs and blog layouts include links for readers to edit the page or create issues for your docs or project via your site&amp;rsquo;s source repository. The current generated links for each docs or blog page are:
View page source: Brings the user to the page source in your docs repo. Edit this page: Brings the user to an editable version of the page content in their fork (if available) of your docs repo.</description></item><item><title>Taxonomy Support</title><link>https://t.is-local.org/en/docs/adding-content/taxonomy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://t.is-local.org/en/docs/adding-content/taxonomy/</guid><description>Docsy supports Hugo&amp;rsquo;s Taxonomies (see: https://gohugo.io/content-management/taxonomies/) in its docs and blog section. You can see the default layout and can test the behavior of the generated links on this page.
Terminology To understand the usage of taxonomies you should understand the following terminology:
Taxonomy a categorization that can be used to classify content - e.g.: Tags, Categories, Projects, People Term a key within the taxonomy - e.g. within projects: Project A, Project B Value a piece of content assigned to a term - e.</description></item><item><title>Diagrams and Formulae</title><link>https://t.is-local.org/en/docs/adding-content/diagrams-and-formulae/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://t.is-local.org/en/docs/adding-content/diagrams-and-formulae/</guid><description>Docsy has built-in support for a number of diagram creation and typesetting tools you can use to add rich content to your site, including \(\KaTeX\), Mermaid, Diagrams.net, PlantUML, and MarkMap.
\(\LaTeX\) support with \(\KaTeX\) \(\LaTeX\) is a high-quality typesetting system for the production of technical and scientific documentation. Due to its excellent math typesetting capabilities, \(\TeX\) became the de facto standard for the communication and publication of scientific documents, especially if these documents contain a lot of mathematical formulae.</description></item></channel></rss>