<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on Tommas's Blog</title><link>https://t.is-local.org/en/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on Tommas's Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://t.is-local.org/en/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docsy 0.10.0 release report</title><link>https://t.is-local.org/en/blog/2024/05/01/docsy-0.10.0-release-report/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://t.is-local.org/en/blog/2024/05/01/docsy-0.10.0-release-report/</guid><description>The big news with Docsy 0.10.0 is color themes and dark mode!
Hugo: breaking changes and deprecation notices In this release, Docsy&amp;rsquo;s Hugo dependency is upgraded to 0.125.4 from 0.122.0. An important thing to note here is that Hugo 0.123.0 was a significant upgrade that included some breaking changes. Before upgrading to this Docsy version, review Hugo&amp;rsquo;s deprecation notices and breaking changes since 0.122.0.
Hugo version support reminder Each Docsy version officially only supports the Hugo version specified in the project&amp;rsquo;s package.</description></item><item><title>Docsy 0.9.0 release report</title><link>https://t.is-local.org/en/blog/2024/02/09/docsy-0.9.0-release-report/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://t.is-local.org/en/blog/2024/02/09/docsy-0.9.0-release-report/</guid><description>Docsy 0.9.0 is a sizable1 release (containing 65+ PRs) that has some breaking and notable changes worth calling out, namely those related to:
Footer improvements Repository links and other page info Look and feel Thank you to all contributors!
Footer improvements For a list of all footer improvements and fixes included in this release, see #1818. We mention a few in this section. More footer improvements, for even easier customization, are planned for the next major release (#1852).</description></item><item><title>Docsy priorities for 2024</title><link>https://t.is-local.org/en/blog/2023/11/28/docsy-priorities-for-2024/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://t.is-local.org/en/blog/2023/11/28/docsy-priorities-for-2024/</guid><description>TL;DR 1.4K projects use Docsy! The top user-project focused priorities for 2024 are: improving Docsy&amp;rsquo;s stability, usability &amp;amp; customizability, and cohesiveness while performing feature consolidation.
Docsy is a popular theme The Hugo-Docsy tool combo is powerful and effective, as I&amp;rsquo;ve blogged about elsewhere. It&amp;rsquo;s maybe no surprise then, to see Docsy used by 1.4K projects1. Why is Docsy popular? I can&amp;rsquo;t say for sure, but I use and recommend Docsy because it has the core features &amp;mdash; necessary for publishing non-trivial tech-doc sites &amp;mdash; that projects seem to want and need, including support for versioning, multiple languages, auto-generated site navigation, and more.</description></item><item><title>Upgrading to Docsy 0.7 &amp; Bootstrap 5</title><link>https://t.is-local.org/en/blog/2023/08/03/upgrading-to-docsy-0.7-bootstrap-5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://t.is-local.org/en/blog/2023/08/03/upgrading-to-docsy-0.7-bootstrap-5/</guid><description>Last June, Docsy celebrated a significant milestone with the release of version 0.7.0. This major upgrade was the result of six months of meticulous work (#470) focused on the migration to Bootstrap 5.2. For highlights and the rationale behind that journey, see Migrating to Bootstrap 5.2.
This blog post is intended to help those who are upgrading to Docsy 0.7 and Bootstrap 5, based on my Docsy 0.7 upgrade experiences, specifically related to Bootstrap.</description></item><item><title>Migrating to Bootstrap 5.2</title><link>https://t.is-local.org/en/blog/2023/06/05/migrating-to-bootstrap-5.2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://t.is-local.org/en/blog/2023/06/05/migrating-to-bootstrap-5.2/</guid><description>Docsy, and Docsy-based project websites (including those at the CNCF), have been happily using the Bootstrap CSS framework from Docsy&amp;rsquo;s inception. In January of this year, Bootstrap 4 (the version used by Docsy for the past few years) reached its end of life. While we, the Docsy steering committee, have been eager to benefit from the Bootstrap 5 improvements, we were concerned about the magnitude of the migration effort, as well as the impact on downstream projects.</description></item><item><title>Hello Docsy!</title><link>https://t.is-local.org/en/blog/2022/04/07/hello-docsy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://t.is-local.org/en/blog/2022/04/07/hello-docsy/</guid><description>Hello It may seem strange to see a &amp;ldquo;Hello&amp;rdquo; post from a project that&amp;rsquo;s several years old, but as Docsy matures as a community-driven project, we thought it was time to (re)introduce ourselves and talk about what&amp;rsquo;s new with your favorite (we hope) Hugo documentation theme!
Discuss amongst yourselves Our Discussions are really hopping lately! Don&amp;rsquo;t miss our notice of the upcoming deprecation of the Font-Awesome and Bootstrap git submodules or our announcement of our new governance model!</description></item></channel></rss>